Software Engineer L2 at Metacube Software Pvt. Ltd.

SUMMARY



Experienced and certified Salesforce Developer with 3+ years of expertise in customer relationship management and implementation. Proactive in delivering tailored solutions for business clients and excel at enhancing user experiences. Being a supportive team player, I am always ready to go the extra mile to assist and collaborate effectively.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Metacube Software Pvt Ltd Jaipur, Rajasthan, India Software Engineer L2 July 2024 - Present
- Software Engineer July 2022 - July 2024

- Developed Salesforce solutions on Sales Cloud to deliver project management and resource allocation/management functionalities for two major IQVIA projects: IQVIA PSA and IQVIA OWF.
- Worked closely with business stakeholders to gather requirements, assess needs, and provide efficient Salesforce solutions that align with business goals.
- Utilized Agile methodology to deliver features in iterative sprints, actively contributing to sprint planning, execution, and retrospectives.
- Engineered 10+ reusable Lightning Web Components utilizing Salesforce Lightning Design System, accelerating UI development by 40% and ensuring consistent enterprise-level design patterns across the IQVIA PSA project.
- Developed and optimized generic LWC components for reusability across multiple projects.
- Led the creation of Proof of Concepts (POCs), optimized project flow and code for better scalability and performance.
- Optimized SOQL queries and code logic to enhance system performance, reduce governor limit issues, and improve the efficiency of data processing.
- Designed and configured Salesforce Flow and Workflow Rules to automate business processes, reducing manual intervention and increasing operational efficiency.
- Ensured compliance with Salesforce security standards, including setting up proper profiles, permission sets, and field-level security for data protection.
- Created Apex Triggers to automate business processes, developed Batch Apex classes for bulk data processing, and wrote unit tests to ensure code quality and coverage.
- Implemented Apex unit tests and code coverage to ensure high-quality, bug-free releases and compliance with Salesforce deployment standards.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Salesforce Development
- Lightning Web Components (LWC)
- · Apex Programming
- · SOQL, SOSL
- Integration
- · Salesforce Lightning Design System
- · Javascript, Python
- HTML, CSS, ReactJS, Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering JECRC University, Jaipur 78% | 2018 - 2022

Higher Secondary Education

SK Greenwood School(CBSE) with 77% | 2017

Secondary Education

Tagore International School(CBSE) with 7.8 CGPA | 2015

SOCIAL LINKS

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ronak-agarwal-63b27b270

Trailblazer Profile: salesforce.com/trailblazer/Rkumpawat99

CERTIFICATIONS

- · Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I
- · Salesforce Al Associate
- · Salesforce Al Specialist
- · Salesforce Associate